<sect1 id="install-installation" xreflabel="Installation">
  <title>Installation</title>

  <para>This document describes how to install the Content Management
    System in conjunction with ACS 4.x.</para>

  <sect2 id="install-install-acs-4x" xreflabel="Install ACS 4.x">
    <title>Install ACS 4.x</title>

    <para>
<!-- This should be displayed on the right side of the page with text
     flowing around it.  DSSSL won't cooperate, though.  Instead we must
     use the old <graphic> tag. -->
<!--
      <inlinemediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata align="right" format="GIF" width="247" depth="176" fileref="images/cms-acs-relationship.gif"/>
	</imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject>
-->

      <graphic align="right" format="GIF" width="247" depth="176" fileref="images/cms-acs-relationship.gif"/>


CMS is essentially an administrative interface built on the ACS
      4.x data model and stored procedure API. You must <ulink url="http://www.arsdigita.com/download">download</ulink> and install ACS
      4.x prior to installing CMS. The ACS 4.x documentation includes an
      excellent guide to the entire process of configuring Oracle and
      AOLserver in addition to installing ACS itself.</para>

    <para>CMS depends on a variety of core ACS packages, which are included
      in the standard ACS 4.x distribution.</para>

    <para>CMS is typically deployed in conjunction with a public web
      service built on ACS. CMS can either run on the public web server or
      on a dedicated server, using either a separate domain name or port
      number from the public server. The production staff uses CMS to
      create, manage and deploy content for the public web service. In
      either scenario, the public server(s) access the published content in
      one of two ways:
    </para>

    <para><phrase>SQL and the Content Repository API</phrase>. Provided
      your public servers have access to the same database schema as CMS,
      you can use SQL queries in conjunction with the Content Repository
      API to access content objects and attributes dynamically on a
      per-request basis.
    </para>

    <para><phrase>Publish to File System</phrase>. CMS can merge published
      content with a template chosen by the publisher and write the output
      to the file system. The output files may be static HTML, or may
      themselves have dynamic includes appropriate for your public web
      server(s) (i.e. ADP, PHP, JSP, ASP, SSI, etc.).
    </para>

    <para>Note that although you must install ACS 4.x for CMS, you are not
      required to use ACS 4.x as part of your public server architecture.
      If you choose to publish all content to the file system, a
      connection between your public web server(s) and the database is
      likewise optional.
    </para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="install-downloading-and-installing-cms" xreflabel="Downloading and Installing CMS">
    <title>Downloading and Installing CMS</title>
    
    <para>The latest release of CMS is always available from the <ulink url="http://cms.arsdigita.com/download.html">CMS download page</ulink> or
      from the <ulink url="http://www.arsdigita.com/download">ArsDigita
	download page</ulink>.
    </para>

    <para> The Arsdigita Package Manager takes care of all the nitty-gritty
      details of installing a package such as CMS. After you have installed
      ACS 4.x, it is available at <ulink
      url="/acs-admin/apm/"><filename>/acs-admin/apm/</filename></ulink> on
      your server.
    </para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="install-getting-started" xreflabel="Getting Started">
    <title>Getting Started</title>
    
    <para> After installation, you need to mount CMS using the ACS' site
      map. It is available on your server at 
      <ulink url="/admin/site-map/">
	<filename>/admin/site-map</filename></ulink>. CMS uses a few
	parameters which you can modify from the same page once you have
	mounted it.
    </para>

    <para>
      <ulink url="mailto:karlg@arsdigita.com">karlg@arsdigita.com</ulink>
    </para>
    <para>
      Last revised: $Id$
    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>



<!--
 Local Variables:
 mode: sgml
 sgml-parent-document: ("index.xml" "chapter" "sect1")
 End:
-->
