<sect2 id="page-relation" xreflabel="Relating Pages, Content Items and Templates">
  <title>Relating Pages, Content Items and Templates</title>

  <para>Consider the site map for a simple dynamic, content-rich
    site:</para>

  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata format="GIF" fileref="images/sitemap.gif"/>
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>

  <para>Each page in the site map corresponds to an item in the content
    repository. Note that the pages in the site map have two basic
    relationships to the actual content of the site:</para>

  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <simpara>The majority of the pages in the site are dedicated to
	displaying the body and attributes of individual content items or
	small logical collections of items, such as the photos on an album
	page.</simpara>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <simpara>In addition to the content pages themselves, publishers must
	implement index pages to provide context for the content of the
	site. These top-level pages provide an interface for searching and
	navigating among the sections of the site and for reaching recent
	or featured content. Besides index pages, the site may also have
	special pages without a direct relationship to content.</simpara>

      <simpara>In order to be represented in the site map and managed in a
	consistent fashion, top-level and special pages must also be
	represented as content items. In the simplest case, the content
	type of these items may just be a Basic Item. This is appropriate
	because these pages typically possess little if any content or
	special attributes of their own, acting merely as containers for
	presenting aggregated summary information. If the top-level pages
	of your site do possess special attributes, or if you wish to
	constrain the relations on those pages, then you can also employ a
	subtype.</simpara>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>

  <sect3 id="page-representing-items-as-pages" xreflabel="Representing Items as Pages">
    <title>Representing Items as Pages</title>

    <para>There are two necessary conditions for an item to be represented
      as a page:</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
	<simpara>The item must have a unique URL. This is true for all content
	  items. Just as the absolute path to a file reflects its location
	  within a directory in the file system, the URL for an item reflects
	  its position within the hierarchical organization of the
	  repository. The URL is simply composed of the name of the item
	  preceded by the names of all its parent items.</simpara>

	<simpara>One major difference from a file system is that the URL includes
	  <emphasis>all</emphasis> parent items, regardless of whether they are folders
	  or not. This is necessary to ensure that all URL's are indeed
	  unique.</simpara>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
	<simpara>The item must be associated with a presentation template. For
	  content pages, the template is typically selected from the one or
	  more templates that are registered with the items's content type.
	  For top-level and special pages, the template is typically unique
	  to the page.</simpara>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </sect3>
</sect2>


<!--
 Local Variables:
 sgml-parent-document: ("user-guide.xml" "sect1" "sect2")
 End:
-->
